那时我们在Carrollton
Yeah, so we out on Carrollton,
有个白人死老头和他的臭婆娘开车过来
this ol' white motherfucker and his wife roll up,
问我"小伙子 你知道坡的故居在哪吗" (听成了贫民窟)
he's like, "young man, you know where the Poe House is?"
我说 "大叔 你开玩笑呢吧"
I'm like, "Unc, you kidding me?
"看看这 随便挑一个吧"
"Look around, take your pick. "
这个老家伙又说"坡的故居"
So, the old man, he's like, "the Poe House.
"爱伦·坡故居"
"The Edward Allen Poe House... "
靠 这么快就回来啦
shit, you back already?
这个月头一回啊
First of the month, yo...
我说 "我不认识什么爱伦·坡" (美国作家)
I'm like, "I don't know no Edward Allen Poe. "
老家伙伤心地看着我 像是我让他失望了似的
The man look at me all sad and shit like I let him down...
你我都知道你们不能进去
I know you know you ain't coming in here.
- 什么 - 小妞 我不认识你
- What? - Shorty, I don't know you.
你总认识后屋的Elaine吧
You know Miss Elaine in the back room, right?
这是她的兄弟 Earl 刚从退伍军人医院出来
This her brother, Earl from the V.A. Hospital.
他来投靠她
He supposed to stay with her.
能帮我把他弄进去吗 我是Chantal
Can you help me inside? I'm Chantal.
你好啊
So, what's good?
谢谢你啊 小伙子
Thank you, young man.
哦 妈的
Oh shit.
啊 别 别...
Nah, nah, nah...
嘿 Omar
Hey, yo, Omar.
恕我冒昧 这个地方
Yo, all due respect, but this right here,
可是Barksdale的地盘
this a Barksdale joint, man.
还用你说
Do tell.
火线重案组 第三季 第二集 先礼后兵
The Wire S03E02 All Due Respect
* When you walk through the garden *
* You gotta watch your back *
* Well I beg your pardon *
* Walk the straight and narrow track *
* If you walk with Jesus *
* He's gonna save your soul *
* You gotta keep the devil *
* Way down in the hole *
* He's got the fire and the fury *
* At his command *
* Well you don't have to worry *
* If you hold on to Jesus hand *
* We'll all be safe from Satan *
* When the thunder rolls *
* Just gotta help me keep the devil *
* Way down in the hole *
* You gotta to keep the devil *
"从来没有过一个这样的纸袋"  ---Colvin
你们觉得这个男孩 昨天起床的时候
You think this boy woke up yesterday morning,
坐在床边会想到自己今天会死?
sat on the edge of his bed and said: "Today's my day to die?"
你们觉得这事不会发生在自己身上?
You don't think this can happen to you?
医生 把那个拿起来
Doc, hold that up.
看看这颗子弹怎么毁了他的心脏
Look at what that bullet did to his heart.
那是他的心脏
That's his heart.
这算什么 威慑教育?
What was that, scared straight?
还不如说是无聊透顶
More like bored stiff.
这是啥玩意儿?
What's the deal with this?
我今天去了州立监狱 想探视个服刑的小子
I go down to M.C.I. Jessup hoping to pull up a fella with some years on him,
瞧瞧他是否想吐露心声
see if he's ready to share his feelings.
结果发现 Barksdale D'Angelo上吊自杀了
Turns out Barksdale D'Angelo got himself rung up as a suicide.
死亡日期 03年7月21日
D.O.D. of 72103.
谁调查的?
Who worked it?
州警
State police.
你想让我给他做尸检?
You want me to pull the postmortem on this?
嗯 可以说是我们害他坐牢的
Yeah, he's kind of our made guy down there.
我只是想确定他的自杀 不是别人动的手脚
I just want to make sure that nobody did the suicide to him.
那里现在一片残砖断瓦
Ain't nuthin' but dust an' bricks over there now.
该死的 我们当初攻城略地的血汗啊
Shit, all that battlin' we did to take them towers.
你是想告诉我 我们只能和别人一起再站大街?
You're trying to tell me we back on the street with the rest of 'em.
不管怎么样 B
Anyway, b,
既然高楼已经没了 所有人都知道事情会不妙
now that the towers is gone everybody knows how it gotta go down.
我说还是早点把我们的人派出去
I say we send our people over there early.
跟那些街头霸王说"我们来了"
Corner chiefs like: "Yo, we here now,
"你们懂我的意思 但我们也带了东西来"
"you know what I mean, but we bringing something to the table."
然后拿出来 像天上掉馅饼一样
Lay it out like it's their lucky day.
不装孙子 也不装老子 让他们觉得这是件好事
No flexing, no threats. Just be like, this a good thing.
但你知道我们需要好地头
But you know we gonna need good corners,
需要靠近市中心
that's what we're gonna need. Close to downtown.
有生意的地方
Get the workaday trade.
- 比如Freemont街 - 还有Fayette
- Come out like Freemont - Fayette.
没错 每天都能轻松进账4到5万
Yeah, like 40, $50,000 a day, easy.
嗯 我去布置
Yeah, I'm on it.
要知道这个时候 所有人都在盯着我们
You know everyone watching us on this, man.
他们想看看 楼没了 我们是不是也跟着完蛋
They wanna see if we're gonna fuck this up now that the towers are down.
你懂我的意思吗 他们是在掂量我们
You know what I'm sin'? They measurin' us up.
他们想瞧瞧 我们是狗熊还是英雄
They wanna see if we're gonna be weak or real.
如果哪个傻瓜想欺到我们头上 我们该怎么做就怎么做
If a fool step to us, man, we gonna do what we gotta do.
但是你进这里是因为死人
But it's them bodies that got you in here.
所以如果可以不杀人 我们就不杀人
If we can do this without the bodies, we should.
明白吗 尤其是现在我们欠打手
You know what I mean? Especially now we light on muscle.
说到打手 我给你派去的那个人有音讯了吗?
Speakin' of muscle, man, you heard from that man I sent you?
嗯 出狱的Cutty 他给我打了电话 我们会招呼他的
Yeah, Cutty from the cut. He rang, we took care of him.
很好
Good, good.
听证会准备得怎么样了
How you fixed for the hearing?
很好 妈的
It's all good, man. Shit.
Levy把一切都打理好了
Levy got everything straightened up tight for me, man.
天凉之前我就可以回家了
I'll be home before it get cold.
高楼都倒了
Towers came down.
所以呢
So?
所以我们要入驻
So, we're comin' in.
来我的地盘? 这可不行
To my corners? I don't think so.
等等 这对你也有好处
Hold on now. This is gonna be good for you too...
是吗? 你怎么会这么想的?
Yeah? Now, how you figure that?
嘿  你进价多少? 3万7还是3万8?
Yo, what you payin' now, 37, 38?
我们可以开3万1  3万2 伙计 而且这货可给力了
Yo, we can go 31, 32 shots. Man, this shit's so John Blaze
就算稀释个7,8倍 依旧销魂
you can step on it seven, eight times and still take the cake...
"蜘蛛包"!
Spider bags!
妈的
Damn!
你们看到Marlo没?
Yo, y'all seen Marlo?
没看见他吗?
Y'all ain't seen him?
你们认识他吗
Y'all know him?
Marlo?
对 他之前在这
Yeah, yeah, he was here.
现在不在了
Now he ain't.
来点"蜘蛛包"吧 "蜘蛛包"!
Get those spider bags, spider bags!
天啊 Tommy 可把我乐坏了
Jesus, Tommy, I like to shit
当我抬头
when I looked up
看见你在新闻里 给Erv难堪
and saw you on the news, givin' it to Erv.
你这混蛋 你肯定有什么企图
you fucker, you're up to something.
我什么企图都没有 真的
I'm up to nothing, I'm telling you.
我可以帮他 他也能帮我
I can help him, he can help me.
互相通融
A little itch here, a little scratch there.
这对你来说怎么都是赢 不是吗
This is a win-win for you, ain't it?
要是他不配合 你就用上升的犯罪率击垮他
He won't play? You beat the shit outta him because crime is up.
媒体会喜欢 你也赢了
Press loves it and you score.
相反他若屈服了
Flip-side is that if he caves,
你在市长的核心班子里就多了一个告密者
you get yourself a snitch in the Mayor's inner-circle.
所以 嗯...
So um...
我在你这出戏里又是什么角色?
what's my role in your little drama?
我觉得你可以当掮客 帮我安排一次见面
I thought you might broker a meeting.
你瞧
You know,
帮助你那个大无畏的头儿 注意到我这个委员会的新朋友
help your fearless leader see the light about his new friend on the council.
那我应该告诉他什么
And I should tell him, what?
乖乖就范 否则就多准备点凡士林? (被操的时候可以当润滑剂)
Make nice or invest heavily in petroleum jelly?
嘿 他的屁股 他的选择
Hey, his ass, his choice.
你没和他谈?
You didn't talk to him?
我没能找到这个狗娘养的
I couldn't find the motherfucker.
哥们 我们就这么过去 肯定会有麻烦
Man, we just walk up, we gonna bump.
那边 房子中间 就待儿那
There. Middle of the block, right there.
名字 体重 赔率 胜负
嘿 家伙在哪儿?
Yo, where the whistle at?
嘿 等一下
Hold on.
等Marlo来
Wait for Marlo.
Cheese 你跑哪去了
Yo, Cheese. Where you been at, man?
哥们 不过是条"小白脸"
Nigger, that ain't nothin' but bait.
还是给你的母狗搓搓肥皂吧(洗去骚味)
Just soap your bitch.
谁是我兄弟 你是我兄弟(Dawg 音通"狗" 用来称兄道弟)
Who my dawg? You my dawg.
谁是我兄弟 谁是我宝贝
Who's my Dawg? Who's my baby?
给老爸挣点钱 听到没
You make daddy some money, alright? Yeah.
2万5 押我兄弟
25 large on Dawg.
Cheese!
哈
Yeah.
想要谁都行?(两人开始性幻想游戏)
Anybody I want?
随便谁
Anybody.
我想多要几个
I want more than one.
我想要Olsen姐妹(好莱坞最红姐妹花)
I want the Olsen twins.
都给你 奴隶而已
You got 'em. Slaves.
她们活着就是为了给你泄欲
All they live for is to get you off.
那么你愿意为她们上谁呢?
But so now who you gonna do for 'em?
一个男人 一个体位
One guy, one act, one time.
是 我一旦说出这个人 你就会说
Right. And the minute I name a guy you're gonna be like,
"第一眼我就知道 你是个基佬"
"I knew you were a cocksucker from the first time I laid eyes on you."
Steve McQueen(美国70年代荧幕硬汉)是你的幻想对象吗?
Steve McQueen, huh? That's your fantasy?
你这个躲在柜子里的王八蛋
You fuckin' closet-case motherfucker.
Steve McQueen?
去你妈的 这是想套我
Fuck you, it's a set-up.
Olsen姐妹都要
Both Olsen twins.
Ashley
Ashley.
- Kate - 是Mary-Kate
- Kate. - Mary-Kate.
恩 我欣赏她们的"作品"(两人在时尚界有自己的品牌)
And yeah, I admire their body of work.
都是你的
They're yours.
你要做的只是说一个男人的名字
All you gotta do is name a guy.
我不是受 我是攻
I'm not catching, I'm pitching.
没问题
No problem.
人员退场
Cornermen out of the pit.
放狗
Release your dogs.
没问题 没问题
I got that! Yeah! I got that!
把狗分开!
Break your dogs!
"小白脸" 哼
Bait...
妈的
Oh shit, there it is.
难道就不能选个...
Can it just be like...
绝世丑女?
like this unbearable-looking woman?
比如"黄金女郎"里的老太婆?(一部美国室内喜剧 主演是四位老太)
You know like that old tune from "The Golden Girls"
那个架着厚眼镜片的小老太婆
the short one with the coke-bottle glasses...
选一个男人
A guy.
嗨 说你呢
Hey, yo.
啊?
Huh?
问你个问题
Let me ask you a question.
你们从哪弄的那种帽子 帽檐居然是歪的?
Where do you guys get those hats with the bills over the ears like that?
我跑遍了所有的商店
I go into all the city stores and the only ones I can find
都是只有帽檐在前面的
are the ones with the bills in the front.
都是一样的 只要歪着戴就行了
Naw, it's the same. Just turn it sideways on your head.
谢谢
Thanks. Thank you.
那个是平房区的白痴 就在那儿
That's a knucklehead from the low-rises, right there.
公房区的人都跑出来了
Terrace's spreading out.
我想他们总得去个地方吧
They got to go somewhere, I guess.
我觉得你没必要那么做
Don't think you ought needed to do that.
他没种 丢了我的脸...
He turned cur on me, man...
不
Nah.
我看你是被耍了
I think you got played.
我猜从公房区来的人
So, I'm guessin' from the Terrace
对地界有非分之想
being all cute about the property line.
我就想着等你回来 看看怎么办
I just wanted to wait and see what you wanted us to do about it.
那么 你想我们怎么办
So, what you want us to do?
回去工作
Get back to work.
好吧
Alright.
你的小弟真让我臭大了 那个小混蛋
Your boy really jammed me, that little prick.
新闻上全是
It was all over the news.
那时你还真没个局长的样子
You did not look particularly commissioner-like.
市长也这么说
Mayor told me the same thing.
你可不能周周都出丑
You can't have that shit every week,
如果你还指望你的大人把你转正的话
not if you want His Honor to give you the job permanent.
Tommy平时挺不错的
Tommy's a good kid, usually.
就是想得到什么的时候 会变成刺头
An asspain when he wants something,
但大多数时候 是个好人
but mostly good people.
我他妈的不在乎他怎么样
I don't give a shit what he is.
但你不能总让他给你颜色看吧 Erv
Well, you can't have him pounding on you, Erv.
扔给他块骨头
Throw him a bone,
他就会对你好了
he'll take care of you.
好吧
Alright,
但我绝不会为了这个家伙背叛市长
but I draw the line at going behind the Mayor for this guy.
坐在我这个位置上 就不能扯市长后腿
You can't sit where I'm sitting and backdoor the fucking Mayor.
不好意思 我迟到了
Sorry I'm late, guys.
我的孩子今天有联赛 开场晚了
My kid had a little league game. It started late.
好吧 你们大家谈吧
Well, I'll leave you boys to it.
"愿我今日所促之情谊"
And what I have brought together,
"无人能拆散"(改自马太福音)
let no man tear asunder.
- 他赢了? - 谁?
- He win? - Who?
你家孩子 他的球队
Your kid, his team.
哦 谁还记比分啊?
Oh shit, who keeps score?
开始是有点杠上了
Yeah, it's a little hectic,
但是后来大家都各退一步
but everybody steppin' off at the right time.
那些我们找上门的街头混混
These corner boys we dealin' with?
我觉得他们连自己的人都不听
I don't think they even listen to their own people.
我会和他们谈的
Yeah, I'm gonna talk to peoples.
- 你去了哪里? - Marlo?
- Where you at? - Marlo?
我根本就找不到他
I can't find 'im.
你告诉过我们不要惹是生非 于是我就在小区中间设了个点
And you told us not to start nothin', so I set-up in the middle of the block.
你瞧 就算那样还是会招来不快 我也不知道
You know, even that got hard stares. I don't know.
我觉得撑不了多久
It ain't gonna hold, I don't think.
这个Marlo
This Marlo.
你怎么个努力找法?
How hard you lookin' for him?
好比 你怎么现在没出去 找这个混蛋呢?
Like, why ain't you out there looking for this motherfucker right now?
因为你让我们来这开会啊
'Cause you called this meeting here.
把门关上
Shut the door.
你有什么好消息 伙计?
What's your good news, man.
Omar又闯进了我们的窝点
Omar right inside the stash.
抢走了已经装好瓶的几盎司货 有600支
Couple ounces of raw already vialed, 600.
这个贱人甚至拿走了我的表
Cocksuckers even took my watch.
这已经是他们这个月 第二次冲了我们的窝
Second stash this month they did got to.
我是说 他直呼你大名 String
I mean, he, um, he called you by name, String.
恕我直言 除非你出面制止他
I mean, all due respect, but do like unless you step to him.
否则这事肯定没完没了下去
It's gonna be like this.
好吧 每个据点都加倍人手
Alright, man. Double the muscle on every stash we got.
如果他再来
And if the man comin',
要准备好
make ready for the man.
这不是私人恩怨
It's not personal.
我对天发誓 我绝不记私仇
I swear to God, it's never personal with me.
事实是
Truth is,
我在委员会已经快三年了
I've been a councilman for almost three years now.
它妈的被冷落了好长一段日子
And that's a long fucking time to be ignored.
在Baltimore 白人是不太可能在市里竞选上位
And this being Baltimore, a whiteboy doesn't stand much chance running citywide.
也许可以去立法院  如果那有空缺
Maybe the legislature, if the right seat opens up.
但在那之前 我只能干着这份没有实权的活
But until then, I'm stuck in a job with no power
除了去指挥修补路上的坑洼
except getting potholes filled.
恕我直言 议员
All due respect, Councilman,
你搞我是因为觉得太无聊了?
you're fucking with me because, what, you're bored?
是有一点
A little, yeah.
管它呢 我是说 说到犯罪
And what the fuck. I mean, when it comes to the crime thing,
这个城市需要各方帮助
this city can use all the fucking help it can get.
如果你要找猫腻 那可没有
If you're looking for dirt, there isn't any.
它妈的哪都有猫腻
There's always fucking dirt.
但是现在 我只想知道 怎么样能做得更好
But right now, I'm just looking to know how we could do better.
你只要能给我做到
You give me that much.
我可以私下 满足你的要求
I can try and get you what you need privately.
不需要听证会 不需发布会 不需要哗众取宠
No hearings, no press, no grandstanding.
如果我不合作的话
And if I don't play ball?
那每次去你们委员会 你都会把我往死里整 对吧?
You're gonna have my ass every time I'm in front of your committee, right?
- 我先想到了一件事 - 说
- One thing comes to mind. - Shoot.
我没法把我的警车从修车厂拿回来
I can't get my marked units back from Dickman Street to save my life.
去保养的警车过去几周了都没回来
Cars that are shopped for service don't come back for weeks.
你跟市长说过了?
You tell the Mayor?
你不能说是我说的
Not that you heard it from me.
当然不会
Of course not.
- 这些多少钱? - 一套一万
- How much these? - 10,000 a set.
有谁在他的车上弄一套 就好比弄了个签名在身上
Nigger show that on a ride, he hangin' a sign on himself.
"来抓我吧"
Lock my ass up.
没错
No, shit.
你打算怎么办?
So how you gonna play it?
如果是从平房区来的 那他们就是Avon的人
If they from the Terrace, that's Avon.
我知道
I know.
Avon也快回来了
And Avon, he comin' home, too.
如果你想和解 那是一回事
Well, if you inclined to work something out, that's one thing.
如果不这样
If not?
Avon是块难啃的骨头
Avon can seriously handle up.
我知道
I know.
所以如果你想保住自己的地盘 最好早做准备
So if you want to hold onto what's yours, you best be ready.
还记得Barksdale那个孩子吗
You remember that Barksdale kid?
把所有事都扛下的那个
The one who took all the weight?
恩
mm.
在监狱图书馆的门把手上 上吊自杀了
Tied his neck to a doorknob in the prison library and sat his ass down.
不是吧
I dunno.
有色人种通常不会自杀
Men of color usually don't do themselves.
我的意思是 就拿我来说
I mean, take me, for instance...
是啊 你早有一万个理由去自杀了...
Yeah, I mean. You got all the reason in the world...
但我仍然好好地在这
And yet here I am, still standing.
也许有点偏差
Give or take.
你看了现场照片?
You looked at the scene photos?
没有 根本没拍
Nah, there ain't none.
州警根本是敷衍了事
State police dogged it.
轮到我了 Bunk
My turn, Bunk.
快啊 快 就按第三套方案
Come on, come on. Go with number three.
亲爱的 想点我的歌吗
You gonna play my song, darling? Huh?
- 你要是挑对了歌... - 嘿 Bunk
- You play the right song... - Hey, Bunk.
- 我可以帮你"飙到高音" 宝贝 - 嘿 Bunk
- I can make you hit the high notes, baby. - Hey, Bunk.
- 嘿 是我先看到她的 Jimmy - Bunk
- Hey, look, I saw her first, Jimmy... - Bunk, man.
-  你干什么呢? - 我在Canmden这有套房子
What are you doing? I got a place right here in Canmden.
- 绅士点 - 我很绅士
- Be a gentleman, come on. - I'm bein' a gentleman, man.
我真的没兴趣
I'm really not interested, okay?
我们走吧
Come on, let's go.
你很害羞啊 宝贝
You're all pink, baby.
太抱歉了 他喝多了
I'm really sorry, he's had a bit too much to drink, you know?
没关系 谢谢
It's okay, thank you, thanks.
你还好吗
You alright?
恩
Yeah.
能自己回家吗
You get yourself home?
能
Yeah.
加油
Knock it out.
- 知道谁最坏吗 - 谁?
- Naw, the baddest nigger of all time? - Who?
老早那会儿 纽约的老黑 叫Bumpy什么的
This nigger from New York from the olden days, Bumpy something...
- Bumpy? - 是
- Bumpy? - Yo,
他妈的他自己跑到了警察局
he do shit like, run up to a police station by himsself.
- 不是吧 - 你明白我的意思吗 就是那么回事
- Nah. - You know what I'm sayin'? Shit like that.
警察躲都来不及 连连求饶"对不起 对不起啊 Bumpy"
Cops be like hidin', like, "Yo, Bumpy, we sorry, man, we sorry.
"求你走吧 求你了"
"Please go away, please, please!"
"汪"
Woof.
找份能挣钱的活
And obtain gainful employment
避免和有案底的人来往
and refrain from associating with known criminals,
并将你的住处告知本局
and keep this office informed of your residence
包括任何变动
and any change in that residence.
我猜你现在还没工作吧
So I gather you're not working at this particular time.
他们在市场那还有招工摊吗?
They still doin' the morning shape-ups down at the market?
不知道 也不在乎 找份工作 随便什么差事
I don't know and I don't care. Just get a job, any job.
- "汪"? - "汪" 叫得跟狗似的
- "Woof"? - "Woof", like a dog.
妈的 就像是这样 砰
Oh shit, it was like blaow!
是Cheese的手下 Tri
It was Cheese's boy, Tri.
你到底要不要还击啊
So you gonna hit back or what?
你有更清晰的勒痕照吗?
You got a better shot of the ligature?
有 在里面
Yeah, inside.
他怎么了 吊死自己两次?
What he do, hang himself twice?
他可能一直向倾斜 直到昏过去后往下滑
He could have been leaning straight forward until he blacked out then slid down
造成了垂直的一条
which would give you the vertical.
或者是从他的背后这样...
Or how about I come up at him from behind...
然后把他放下 弄成他向这个残酷世界告别的样子
and then set him down, make it look like goodbye cruel world.
现场拍照片怎么说的?
What do the scene shots show?
根本就没拍
None taken.
州警这次偷懒到家了
The troopers really fucked the pooch on this one.
我就只有一份狗屁报告
All I have is some half-assed report
原句:调查员停服了'利他灵' 停服此药会让人萎靡不振
读起来也是干巴巴的
reads like the investigator went off his ritalin.
这块墨水渍真大...
What's a large eckee...
不 那是块瘀斑 后背中央
No, large ecchymotic area, or mid-back.
淤青
Bruising.
什么?后背中央?就像是...
What, mid-back... as in...?
也许是他几天前洗澡 的时候磕到了自己 也许吧
Or he banged himself a few days earlier in the shower. Yeah, maybe.
有个"也许"就够了
Nothing like a definite maybe.
Tri还是得手了
Tri finally got that m?
还是走着去的
Done it on foot too.
Caroline?
小子倒下的地方被描了粉笔(犯罪现场定位)Tri被溅了一袖子
Nigger lyin' in chalk but my boy Tri got the dapple all up his sleeve.
看着像圆点花纹
Looks like polka dots.
这事可得吃一堑得长一智
But that's just something you got to know from experience,
你懂我的意思吗
- You know what I'm sayin'? - mm-hum.
我甚至还得教他怎么处理"家伙" 他居然还随身带着呢
I even had to school him on the whistle, still walkin' around with it.
我说 "Tri 把它藏到Neesey那 你脑子哪儿短路了?"
"Yo Tri, stash that shit up at Neesey'S. What's wrong with you?"
你知道 那些个家伙肯定不会善罢甘休
Aw, you know them niggers is gonna get mad busy over this
所以我们也要忙了
so we gettin' busy too.
那你什么时候过来啊?
So what time you comin' over?
妈的 贱人 你在没在听啊
Damn, bitch, ain't you even listenin'?
嗨 你还在吗
hey. You still there?
收摊
Lay down
暂停
Time-out!
再做一次啊
Do that again.
- 再做一次什么 - 再做一次那个手势
- Do what again? - Do that thing with your hand.
- 当着我的面再做一遍 - 你他妈的说什么呢
- Do it in my face. - Fuck you talkin' about?
车上还空得很呢!
Got a lot of room in here.
去他妈的警察
Fuck the police!
伙计 我们只是随便逛逛
Naw, man, we was just hangin'.
只是贩贩毒吧
Just slingin'.
你们是怎么和原本街头的人妥协的
How'd you work it out with the corner crews,
怎么就大摇大摆从平房区跑这来了?
all you guys from the Terrace coming in like this?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you talkin' about.
你最好小心点 因为这里的毒贩
Well, you best watch your ass. 'Cause the slingers out here?
他们打从娘胎就开始沾毒了
They're like the crack babies' babies.
哥们 每一年大家都会说
Man, every year everybody's like:
"这里的孩子 他们是新一代"
"Yeah, these kids out here, they're a new breed."
"我之前从没见过"
"I ain't never seen nothing like this before."
"旧日子过去了"
"This the end of the world now."
好好看看 这对你来说 像是新一天的开端吗
Look around, fuckhead. This seem like the dawn of a new day to you?
我现在能走了吗
Can I go now?
还是你想先多扇我几巴掌
Or you want to slap me up some more first.
滚
Get the fuck out of here.
- "打飞机"怎么样 - 啊?
How about a handjob? Huh?
哦 你甚至都没敢想 Weezy Jefferson帮你打飞机
Aw, man, you don't even get Weezy Jefferson for a handjob.
嘿
Come on.
- Dozerman  - 收工吗
Dozerman. Wanna call it a day?
他们这回来寻仇了
They came back on us this time.
Dazz的人 他们找上了Peanut
Dazz an' them. They got Peanut.
哦 妈的 Peanut死了吗
Oh, shit, is Peanut dead?
没有 他"还好"
Naw, he's okay.
他的脑浆都撒在人行道上了 不过他"没事"
His brains all over the sidewalk but he's okay.
你他妈的想什么呢
What the hell do you think?
妈的 我要给Tony打电话 我回头再打给你
Ah, shit, I gotta call Tony. I'll get back Atchya.
好吧
Alright.
哦 我们已经听到两件了
Well, that's two we heard about.
发生什么事了
What the hell's going on?
也许是毒品大战?
Drug war maybe?
怎么样?
S'up?
不怎么样
Nothing good, man.
自从我把他杀了 我就睡不着觉了
I ain't sleep since I capped his ass.
我一闭上眼睛 就看到他 在血泊里的样子
Close my eyes, see him layin' there all bloody and shit.
Cheese 你做了必须得做的
Cheese, man, you did what you had to do.
我自认该做的事
What I thought I had to do.
那是Cheese?
That's Cheese?
他是我的"哥们"(狗 两者同音)
He was my Dawg, yo.
以前非常爱我
Had much love for me, even then.
我再也找不到像他这样的了...
I ain't never gonna find another Dawg like that...
已经叫他们付出了代价
well, they payin' for it now.
一点没错
Mos' def.
几个月里 这些混蛋在电话里一直口风很紧
For months, these assholes show perfect phone discipline.
现在他们却大谈起了谋杀?
Now, they're talking up murders?
Chesse的地位仅次于Proposition Joe
Cheese is only a level below Proposition Joe.
突然之间 案子又有眉目了
All of a sudden, this case has legs.
杀人...
Homicide...
我是Freamon 专案组
This is Freamon, major-case.
今晚的值班警官是谁?
Who's the O.I.C. tonight?
我帮你转Norris
Hold on for Norris.
- 哦 T... T... - 发生什么了?
- Yo, T., T., Man. - S'up?
我中枪了 我中枪了
I'm shot, I'm shot.
哦 妈的 妈的 他们找上门了
Aw shit, shit, they comin' back.
狗娘养的!
Motherfucker!
谁?
Who this?
妈的
Damn.
Norris警探
Detective Norris.
Ed 我是Lester
Ed, this is Lester.
我听说在东区发现了尸体
I hear you're catchin' bodies on the east side.
"听说"? 是"捕风捉影"的听说?
You "hear" it? Like what, "probable cause," hear it?
还是"有跟有据"的听说?
Like, "I got something concrete," hear it?
还是"无中生有"的听说?
Or just, "gas up my head," hear it?
好比 "我有的是时间跟你撂磕"的听说?
Like, "I got all the fucking time in the world to jaw with you," hear it?
你那死了多少人 Eddie?
How many bodies you got, Eddie?
"死了多少人 Eddie?"
"How many you got, Eddie?"
混蛋
Asshole.
- 你需要我去趟凶杀科吗 - 不用 我去就好
- You want me to go up to homicide? - No, I got it, I got it.
你明天值早班 赶紧回家吧
You're the early man on tomorrow, so go home.
看看你的孩子
See your kid.
我告诉你  这个Berman太牛叉了
I'm telling you, this kid Berman's a fucking wizard.
我是说 你看看
I mean check it out, right?
六起举报的汽车窃案
Six reported auto thefts,
其中两起"不排除被借走的可能"
two of which state, "not impossible car was borrowed"
于是它们证据不足 不予立案  只剩其余四起
making four auto thefts, with two unfounded.
而里头最牛叉的呢? 要属四起武装抢劫
And the prizewinner? Four armed robberies,
其中两起受害人抱怨说 "天太黑 无法辨认武器"
two of which complainants state, "too dark to I.D. weapon,
"不排除是假刀的可能"
not impossible knife wasn't a com.."
- 他也许能全整没了 - 是啊
- He mighta groomed 'em to death. - Yeah...
苦酒变甘泉啊
Wine into water.
说曹操 曹操到
There he is.
Abbadabba Berman
Abbadabba Berman.
Atkins是一种以发明人命名的减肥法
罪案的"瘦身博士"
The Doctor Atkins of crime.
我只是奉命行事
Just doing what I'm told.
天啊 多美的电影
God, what a beautiful film.
我一个字都听不懂
I couldn't understand a word.
哦 亲爱的 你应该看看字幕
Oh, honey, you gotta read the subtitles.
哦 妈的
Oh shit.
你们都来看电影啦
Y'all go to the movies?
你一定是可爱的Herc夫人吧
And you must be the lovely Mrs. Herc.
喜欢你看的电影吗
How'd you like your movie?
还行吧
Okay.
Herc和Carver这两位
Herc and Carver here?
他们每天都想把我们抓起来
They try to snatch us up everyday like...
比如问"东西在哪呢" "谁手上藏了"
where the shit, who got the shit...
但是从没找到过
but they never get nothing.
所以你们只能来看电影了
So y'all go to the movies.
妈的
Damn.
就这样吧 明天见
Alright then. See ya tomorrow.
没事吧?
Is everything okay?
2号线
On two.
接电话! 接电话!
Pick up! Pick up!
- Ed 你得帮帮我 - 现在不行
- Ed, you gotta help me. - I can't, now now.
那么
So.
什么
So?
都还好吧?
Everything good?
鲁门怎么样了?
How's that fontanette?
婴儿出生时头顶两块没有骨质的“天窗"
是卤门
Fontanelle.
要闭合了吗
Is it closing up?
暂时还不能
Won't close for a while.
很好
Good.
这算好?
Good?
我只是 只是随便说说
I'm just, I'm just sayin'.
六个人 六块钱
Seis hombres, seis dolares.
六个人...
Seis hombres...
"杀了他之后我就再没睡过好觉"
I ain't sleep since I capped his ass.
"一闭上眼睛就能 看见他倒在血泊里的样子"
Close my eyes an' see him layin' there all bloody and shit?
- Cheese - 磁带里的Cheese
- Cheese. - Cheese on a platter.
他从不这么说话
He never talks like that.
为什么现在会...
Now, why would...
因为天道酬勤呗
because all good things come to those who wait.
- McNulty知道了吗? - 我来叫醒他
- Does McNulty know? - I'll raise his ass.
我们可以继续监听他们的电话 搜集有关String的线索 没问题
We'll keep our ears to the wire keep gathering String, no problem.
但是如果东区继续出凶案
But if bodies keep falling in the Eastern District,
我们可能就得放弃监听了
we might have to give up this wire tap.
你现在过来干嘛
Now you comin' around?
都他妈的一年多了
Been more than a dam year.
长得可真像他老爸
Looks just like his dad, huh?
我就是想问问你
Let me ask you.
当你听说Dee自杀的时候 你是怎么想的
When you heard Dee was a suicide, what'd you think?
嗨 小家伙 过来
Hey, little fellow. Come here.
是这样的 我们得到消息
Here's the thing: we got a tip.
尸检结果也佐证了它
And the autopsy report it backs us up.
你能把他放下吗
Can you put him down please?
当然了
Sure.
你瞧 对于他的死我感到很抱歉
You know, I'm sorry about your loss.
总的来说 他还算是个好人
He seemed like a pretty decent guy, all things considered.
所以当我发现这事时
So when I found out about this,
我觉得是我欠了他的
I felt like I owed him...
我最不想做的就是让你无事生忧
the last thing I wanted to do was upset you if there was no point to it, so...
所以如果有什么可以帮忙的 或者你有想追问的
if there's anything I can help with or any questions you need answered...
任何事情
or whatever.
James Mcnulty警探 凶杀组
警长 你手下有多少人
Major, how many people are under your command?
278个 长官
278, Sir.
278个 上月他们一共逮捕了多少重案犯?
278. And how many felony arrests they make last month?
不用看了
Don't bother.
16个
You made 16.
才16个
16.
在一个月里
In a month.
这段时间里 你们缴获了多少手枪?
Same time period. How many handguns you pick up?
算上所有班组 所有单位...
All shifts, all sectors...
再说一遍 不用翻了 答案是零
once again, don't bother. The answer is none.
鸭蛋
None.
昨晚在多少小时内出现了四具尸体?
You had four bodies last night in how many hours?
你他妈地合上笔记 是几小时?
Shut the fucking book, how many hours?
七小时
Seven.
五小时才对吧
Try five.
跟我说说这个孩子
Tell me about this kid.
- 他应该是叫James - James Toney
- I believe his name is James... - James Toney.
他上次被捕是什么时候
When's the last time he was arrested?
和谁一起
With who?
他在哪儿贩毒?
Where's he sling?
这个家伙呢
How about this guy?
这个呢? 这个呢?
Or him? Or him?
你知道吗 四具尸体 互相只隔了两个街区
You know what? You got four bodies, all within two blocks of each other
你甚至连他们之间的关联点都没去找
and you can't even start to connect the fucking dots.
我给你8个小时把它搞定了 要不你就死定了 听到没?
You got eight hours to get a grip on this mess or you're done. You hear me?
死定了
Done.
Marlo
Marlo?
你知道我是Avon的人吧
You know I'm with Avon, right?
Stringer Bell
Stringer Bell?
咱们能谈谈吗
Can we talk?
我要你滚回去 把你的人都带走
I need you to walk back up there and pack up your people.
趁我现在还跟你客气
I'm being a gentleman about it for the moment.
要是你们打算利用手头的情报 那就得抓紧时间了
You offer up what you have on this, you start the clock running on yourselves.
监听行动势必会在法庭上暴露 没别的办法
The wiretap has to surface in court. No way around it.
她说得对
She's right.
我们好不容易听到了有价值的东西 现在你却让我们放弃?
We finally got something worth listening to and you're talking about giving up the wire?
- 没有道理啊 - 火拼已经开始了
- Makes no sense. - There's a war going on.
我们今晚可能又会多出四具尸体
We might have four more bodies tonight.
这可是Baltimore 六具还差不多
This is Baltimore, we might have six.
我今天看到东区的Marvin Taylor
I watched Marvin Taylor from the Eastern
因为办案不利而被训得狗血淋头
get his asshole ripped today because he has no fucking clue.
太扯淡了
I don't believe this.
我们既然已经听到了头目在谈论谋杀
We got top lieutenants talking about murders,
我们不去自己查明 反而得终止行动 杀鸡取卵?
and we can't figure out just to shut up and take notes?
这么多人横尸街头 Jimmy 这不算小事了
We got bodies on the ground, Jimmy. That's gotta matter for something.
如果我们掌握了Cheese 那我们就接近了Prop Joe
Look, if we're at Cheese then we're close to Prop Joe,
如果我们接近了Joe 那离Stringer也就不远了
and if we're close to Joe, then we're close to Stringer.
那才重要
That has to matter.
瞧 我和你一起看着Stringer逍遥法外
Look, I was right there with you when we left Stringer on the street
我也很难受
and it grinds me, too.
但事实是 我们这个小组不是专门抓毒贩的
But the fact is, we didn't create this unit just to lock up dope dealers.
我们有干这事的缉毒队
There's a narcotics unit downtown for that.
我们是对抗暴利犯罪 从一开始就是如此
We're about violence. Have been from the jump.
Barksdale是暴徒
Barksdale was violent.
但是现在 Stringer一点动静都没有
But right now, Stringer's quiet,
而东区却是血流成河
and over on the eastside, we got bodies.
Jimmy 我们的监听情报
Jimmy, we got enough from the tap
已经足够给Cheese狠狠一击了
to take a real good shot at Cheese.
你们拿一 两件凶案定罪
You put a murder case or two together,
也许能让谁把Joe 或者Stringer供出来
you may be able to roll someone up at Proposition Joe or Stringer.
就尸体来说 四个已经很多了
As far as bodies go, four's a big number.
那好吧
Okay then.
现在 我们用那些电话来查这些谋杀案
As of now, we use the phones to work these murders.
我需要有人再修剪一下那里的灌木(西班牙语)
Yo quiero mucho menos pastillas de secoya en eso.
长得太开了
Y muy mas ancho un poco.
好吗? 谢谢
Si? Gracias.
嘿 我们要出发了
Yo, we bracin' up, son. Hanh?
打起精神来 小子 我们得去会会Dazz
Gather yo'self, nigga. We gotta bead on Dazz.
一小时后在Neesey的屋子见
Be at Neesey's crib in a hour.
Dazz和Neesey在一起? 我还以为她是你的妞呢
Dazz be with neesey? I thought she was your girl.
- Neesey 查到了 - 我们在那碰头 然后开打
Neesey, huh? Got it. We just hook up there, then goin' to battle.
带上你的家伙 一小时后见
Bring your whistle, in a hour, one.
出发
Mount up.
Caroline 向快速反应部队报告位置 然后继续监听
Caroline, call qrt with that 20 and stay on the wire.
- 我们用第二频道联络 - 好
- We're on channel two. - Alright.
嗨 Tri 你想要多大分的薯条
Yo, Tri, what size fries you want?
什么
What?
冲!
Go!
警察 不许动 把手举起来
Police! Freeze! Hands up!
把手举起来
Put your hands up!
把手举起来 把手举起来
Put your hands up! Hands on your head!
好吧 Mary Tyler Moore(电视剧演员)一丝不挂
Okay, Mary Tyler Moore. Buck-naked.
把门打开 我走进去
Open the door, here I come,
扔了我的公文包 弯下了她那小蛮腰
drop my attache case down, bend her over,
在垫脚凳上操她 她叫着:
give it to her on the ottoman, and she's like,
"啊Rob 啊Rob... "
"Oh Rob, oh Rob... "
Rob是谁
Who's Rob?
剧里的人物 结束
From the show. Done.
Mary-Kate和Ashley... 我不想多说
Mary-Kate and Ashley... I don't want to say.
我脑子里的场景已经够了
Just accept whatever pictures are on my mind right now.
还有别人吗
Anybody else?
恩 Dozerman的那个妞 她叫什么来着
Yeah, Dozerman's girl, what's her name?
她全裸着 烤着蛋糕
She's baking a cake. Naked.
雪白的面粉溅落在她 美好的棕色肌肤上
White flour splotches all over her fine brown skin.
我进去了 只戴着一顶厨师帽 什么都没穿
I come in, in a chef's hat, nothing else on,
"老二"挺身而出 说
johnson out to here and say,
"面不是这么和的"
"that's no way to stir a batter.
"这样 让我来把…"
"Here, let me try to get..."
嘿 Doze
Hey, Doze,
怎么了?
what's up?
好了 现在说男的
Done, now the guy.
这对任何人来说都很难理解
This is a hard one for anybody to understand.
我是说这和性无关
I mean it's got nothing to do with sex.
这是出于同情 男儿也要得到休息
It's about... sympathy. It's about giving a guy a break.
恩 好吧好吧
Yeah, okay, okay.
Gus Triandos
Gus Triandos.
Gus Triandos是谁
Who's Gus Triandos?
Orioles棒球队过去的接球手
A catcher with the Orioles back in the day.
我和我哥都有他的明星卡
Me and my brother had his card,
这丫看起来真可怜
sorry lookin' motherfucker, man.
我是说 他看起来就像是个
I mean, he looked like this little kid
被父母扔在了汽车站的小孩
who got left at a bus station by his parents.
你知道为什么吗
You know why?
因为他得接住Hoyt Wilhelm(同队的著名明星投手)的蝴蝶球
Because he had to catch Hoyt Wilhelm's knuckle ball.
整整五年啊 棒球里最难接的旋转球
Five fucking years, the worst gig in baseball.
就像接一头抹了油 长了翅膀的猪
It was like trying to catch a greased pig with wings.
他有一次甚至对记者说 "Wilhelm几乎把我给毁了"
He even told a reporter once "Wilhelm nearly ruined me."
Gus Triandos
Gus Triandos.
大块头
Big slow guy.
- 不错 - 得了 说吧
- Good choice. - Go ahead, say it.
- 我知道你想说 - 说什么 没什么好说的啊
- I know you want to say it. - Say what? There's nothing to say.
- 没什么? - 你琢磨了很久
- Nothing? - You put a lot of thought into it.
- 很好 - 好吧
- It's cool. - Okay.
听着 今晚记住三件事
Okay. Tonight, three things.
第一件
Number one.
所有行动都要连续编号 不然明天你们就该凌乱了
Keep your incident numbers sequential or it's gonna be a stone mess tomorrow.
第二件 我们会在现场拍照取证
Number two. We'll be photographing evidence at the scene.
就是说在照相之前 什么都不要装进袋里
That means don't bag anything until you get the shot off.
第三件
And number three,
别给自己丢脸
don't embarrass yourselves...
确定你们的相机都上了胶卷
make sure your camera's loaded with film.
就这样 出发
Okay, mount up.
Cheese 谁是你的哥们?
So Cheese, who's your Dawg?
你是我哥们啊
You my Dawg.
我只是想知道谁是你的"哥们" 哥们
I just wanna know who's your Dawg, Dawg.
你们这是心理战吗
What's this some psychology, huh?
那好吧
Yeah, okay, uh,
哦 别说了 别说了 我把知道的一切都告诉你们
"yo, please stop, stop. I'll tell you everything I know."
别这样 Cheese
C'mon, Cheese.
到底谁是你的哥们?
Who's your Dawg?
不会吧 别想把他们赖在我身上
hell no. You ain't layin' no bodies on me, man.
律师该登场了
Lawyer time.
"他是我哥们 伙计"
"He was my Dawg, man."
"自从杀了他我就没睡过一个好觉"
"I ain't sleep since I capped his ass."
"就在血泊里那么看着我"
"Lookin' up at me all bloody and shit?"
"他那时是那么爱我"
"Had much love for me even then."
"我再也找不到像他那样的了"
"I ain't never gonna find another..."
你们他妈的真是些冷血的混蛋
Man, you all some cold-ass motherfuckers, man.
我们已经全录下来了
We got you on tape.
到底发生了什么 Cheese
So what happen, Cheese?
我以为他丢了我的脸 所以我做了必须做的事
I thought he punked me, alright? So I did what I had to do.
是什么呢
Which was...
送他上了西天
Lit him up.
不管怎样 他开口了
Well, he's talking anyway.
不过 覆水难收
Well, what's done is done.
也许我们可以帮帮你
But, maybe we can help you on this.
怎么帮 你能让他复活吗
How? You gonna bring him back?
不 但能给你条后路
No, on the consequences.
帮我们 帮自己
Help us help you.
- 什么 - 也许我们可以做个交易
- What? - Maybe we can trade up.
做什么交易? 为这个?
Trade up for what, man? For this?
- 搞毛 - Proposition Joe
- The fuck... - Proposition Joe.
你跟我们说说Prop Joe 我们也许在这案子上放你一马
You give us Prop Joe and maybe we look at this whole thing with Dawg differently.
我为啥要说Prop Joe啊 和这事....?
Now, why would I be talkin' about Prop Joe behind...
你们瞧 我根本就不认识什么Prop Joe
You know what, man? I don't even know no Prop Joe.
好吧 哥们...
Okay, Dawg...
到底哪个是他 他的尸体在哪
which one of these is he? Where's that body?
应该就在我扔了他的地方吧
Where I left it most likely.
- 东边的仓库 - 他还在那儿?
- Warehouse on the east side. - And he still there?
据我所知应该还在吧 除非动物保护协会去过了
Far's I know. 'Less the SPCA come around.
什么
What?
看来他们突破了他
Looks like they broke him.
我不得不说 这次你们给我看到了点成绩
I got to say. You really showed me something on this.
我还能多说什么呢  我欠你个人情 Cedric
What can I possibly add to that except I owe you one, Cedric.
你有过鱼和熊掌兼得的经历吗?
You ever have one of those have-your-cake-and-eat-it-too days?
这应该会是我的第一次
I believe this could be my first.
告诉我点好消息吧
Tell me something good.
我们要告他
We're charging him.
处置动物不当
Improper disposal of an animal.
越限开枪
Discharging a firearm in city limits.
如果你想搞大 就告他虐待动物吧
Animal cruelty, if you wanna run wild with it.
说吧 说我是个玻璃
Go ahead. Call me a cocksucker.
- 你知道你想 - 什么
- You know you wanna. - Excuse me?
你知道 我还真去查了Gus Triandos的资料
You know, I actually looked up the stats on Gus Triandos.
还是个"强棒"呢 对吧?(双关 操起人来也狠)
Power hitter, right?
你们两个去死吧
Fuck the both of you.
回见 "兄弟"
Later, dawg.
滚吧
Kiss my ass.
- 晚安 Bunk - 晚安
- Night, Bunk. - night.
今天真有意思...
Funny day...
我是阻止了毒品大战的局里新宠
I'm the new departmental pet for shutting down a drug war,
却因一条死狗暴露了整个监听行动
but I blew my wire for a dead terrier.
你记得你是怎么说的吗
You remember how you said
你希望今天是你的第一次
you hoped today would be your first
鱼和熊掌兼得的好日子
have-your-cake-and-eat-it-too day?
怎么了
What about it?
好吧 先生们
Okay, gents.
你们看到刹车灯闪两次
You see the brake lights pump twice,
就意味着我们钓鱼成功
you know we got a clean hand-to-hand.
我今天早上进办公室看到
So I get in this morning and I'm looking at
公共福利部Buddy Ferraro 给我的三条留言
three phone messages from Buddy Ferraro over at D.P.W.
保证把20辆带无线警车
All assuring me that I'll have 20 radio cars
在这周之前还给我
back in service at the end of the week.
Buddy和父亲是老交情了
Buddy and my old man go way back.
他们同在圣里欧教堂接受了"初次圣礼"(儿童初次领食圣餐)
Made their first communion together at St. Leo's.
那么
So...
你还需要什么
what else do you need?
你不是直接找的市长吧?
You didn't go to the Mayor with it?
你拿没拿到车?
Did you get your cars?
有谁因此遭殃吗?
Did anyone get fucked over it?
还是你工作变得更轻松了?
Or did your job just get a little easier?
今年年底我有70个警员退休
I got 70 cops retiring at the end of the year.
据我所知 他们没有培训新员的钱
That I know of and no money for an academy class.
你被市长玩了
The Mayor fucked you
因为我知道预算里原来是有这笔钱的
'cause I know that money was in the budget.
市长把它推迟到了明年夏天
The Mayor delayed it till next summer.
少点警察 就可以少点工资 少点津贴
Less troops, less salary, less bennies.
即使是只推迟6个月 也可以给市里省下2到3百万
Even a six-month delay saves the city two, three million.
让我找人谈谈
Lemme talk to some people.
喂
Yeah.
- Colvin警长? - 是
- Major Colvin? - Yeah.
对不起这么晚给您打电话
I'm sorry to call you this late,
但是有个警察在您的辖区受伤了
but we have an officer down in your district.
哪个医院
Which hospital?
我才刚租下 所以有点…
I, ah, just got the lease, so...
去他妈的单枪匹马!
Fucking solo cars!
我应该和他组队的 我搞砸了
I shoulda teamed him. I fucked up.
混蛋动都不动
Dead-ass motherfucker's dead.
我们追上他的时候 已经醒不过来了
We catch up to him, he don't come in alive.
是吧?
Right?
擦过颈部 下巴被击碎
Nicked jugular, shattered jaw.
命保住了
He'll live.
给我一罐吧
Hand me one of those.
我刚从急创室回来
I just got back from shock-trauma.
多亏了你们的及时送救  救了他一命
You guys saved his ass getting him down as fast as you did.
有疑犯的体貌特征吗?
So what we got for a suspect?
头号嫌烦 男性 白衬衫 宽松的牛仔裤 网球鞋
Number one male, white t-shirt. Baggy jeans, tennis shoes.
仍然在逃 但我们已经封锁了那里
In the wind, but we're locking it down out there.
我听到的那把枪呢?
So what's this I hear about the gun?
Doze想要回击 结果枪掉了
Doze tried to return fire, he dropped his piece.
有个混蛋捡起来跑了
Some fuck picks it up and books.
我真它妈的不敢相信
I mean I can't believe this shit.
给我吧
I'll take it.
不不不...
No, no, no...
等我整理好了 这地方会好点
It'll be nicer when I fix the place up.
Cedric...
我不在乎
I don't care.
不 告诉他我累得直打瞌睡 我刚从医院那出来 筋疲力尽
No, tell him I'm cooked. I just got done at the hospital, I'm all in.
他问你能不能跟记者谈谈
Well, he was askin' if you could maybe talk to the reporters.
他现在不会想让我和记者谈的
He doesn't want me talking to reporters right now.
- 好吧 - 那太不明智了
- Alright. - That would truly be unwise.
- 好吧 好吧 我会告诉他的 - 好的
- Alright, alright, I'll tell him. - Alright.
Bunny 你看起来气色很差
Bunny. You look hellacious.
你那有咖啡吗
You got coffee going in there?
你知道我是怎么想的吗
You know what I was thinking?
今晚其实挺好的 知道为什么吗
Tonight's a good night. Why?
因为中枪的警察没有死
Because my shot cop didn't die.
这让我突然想到
And it hit me...
在我还当班的日子里 已经算是不错的晚上了
this is what makes a good night on my watch:
没有人死
Absence of a negative.
确实是个不错的晚上
That was a good night.
是这样的
Here's the thing.
再过六个月 我就走了
Six months from now? I'm gone.
30年了
I put in my 30
我只在西区大厅留下了
and the only thing that'll be left of me on that job is an
一张8*12的照片
eight-by-eleven framed picture in the western hallway.
但是你知道吗
But you know what?
这个狗屁世道
The shit out there,
这个城市
the city,
比我刚来的时候更乱了
is worse than when I first came on.
人们会怎么说我呢?
So what does that say about me?
我这一生啊...
About my life...
别这样 那可是毒品啊
Aw, c'mon, man. You're talking about drugs.
不可抗拒啊
That's a force of nature.
就像是风扫落叶 管你是谁
That's sweeping leaves on a windy day whoever the hell you are.
你打了漂亮的一仗...
You fought the good fight...
自从向Cheese露了底 就再没听到一个电话
Not a call since we gave it up to Cheese.
你以为呢
What did you expect?
起立
Attention.
坐下吧
Be seated.
关于Dozerman警官
Regarding officer Dozerman,
他已经转入重症监护房
His condition has been upgraded to guarded.
在他能接受访客之后
'Till he can receive visits,
会被转移到康复病房
he's beemoved to the recovery unit.
这次行动以后
As of this tour,
所有对非法贩毒者实施的诱捕行动
all hand-to-hand undercover buys of C.D.S.
将在西区全面暂停
Are suspended in the Western District.
以前
Somewheres
很久以前
back in the dawn of time
这个地区曾经历过 一次史无前例的困境
this district had itself a civic dilemma of epic proportions.
市委员会通过了一项法律
The city council had just passed a law
即禁止在公共场所消费酒精饮料
that forbid alcoholic consumption in public places.
大街上
On the streets
巷子里
and on the corners.
无论是过去 现在 或将来 小巷子一直都是
But the corner is, and it was and it always will be
穷人们休息之所
the poor man's lounge.
炎夏的夜晚他们就在小巷子里乘凉
It's where a man wants to be on a hot summer's night.
那比酒吧便宜
It's cheaper than a bar,
可以吹着晚风 看着路过的美女
catch a nice breeze, watch the girls go by.
但是法律就是法律
But the law's the law
如果西区巡警经过
and the western cops rollin' by,
他们该怎么做
what were they gonna do?
如果因为这样就逮捕他们
If they arrested every dude out there for tipping back a high life
他们就没有时间去办别的案子了
there'd be no other time for any other kind of police work.
如果他们不呢
And if they looked the other way?
那些人就会洋洋得意
They'd open themselves to all kinds of flaunting,
失去应有的敬意
all kinds of disrespect.
虽然这是发生在我上任之前
Now, this is before my time when it happened but,
但在50到60年代之间
somewheres back in the 50s or 60s,
有一个天才的无名小卒
there was a small moment of
发明了一个该死的方法
goddamn genius by some nameless smokehound
一天他从促销店里出来
who comes out the cut-rate one day
在去巷子的路上
and on his way to the corner,
他把刚买的一品脱果酒
he slips that just-bought pint of Elderberry
放到了一个纸袋里
into a paper bag.
这是全民妥协的一个伟大的时刻
A great moment of civic compromise.
那个小小 皱皱的纸袋
That small wrinkled-ass paper bag
让巷子里的人们可以 安安心心地喝酒了
allowed the corner boys to have their drink in peace
也让我们
and gave us permission
可以去办警察的差事
to go and do police work.
那些值得我们努力去办的案子
The kind of police work that's actually worth the effort,
那些值得我们中弹的案子
that's worth actually taking a bullet for.
Dozerman
Dozerman,
他昨晚中弹 不过是为了
he got shot last night trying to buy...
买这三支毒品
three vials.
三支!
Three!
从来没有一个纸袋
There's never been a paper bag...
装过毒品
for drugs.
直到这一刻
Until now.
如果我们不搞诱捕  我们还能怎么样?
If we ain't doing hand-to-hands, then what the fuck?
什么他妈的破纸袋啊
And that shit with the bag?
它妈的搞毛!
What the fuck is that?